<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cherrytree>
  <node unique_id="27" master_id="0" name="Basics" prog_lang="custom-colors" tags="" readonly="0" nosearch_me="0" nosearch_ch="0" custom_icon_id="0" is_bold="0" foreground="" ts_creation="1730999214" ts_lastsave="1731006811">
    <rich_text>
</rich_text>
    <rich_text scale="h3">Metasploit Framework Overview</rich_text>
    <rich_text>
Metasploit is a powerful penetration testing framework that simplifies the process of discovering, exploiting, and managing vulnerabilities. It provides an array of modules to facilitate various penetration testing tasks.

</rich_text>
    <rich_text scale="h4">Key Modules</rich_text>
    <rich_text>
1. </rich_text>
    <rich_text weight="heavy">Auxiliary Modules</rich_text>
    <rich_text>: Tools that assist in tasks such as scanning, fuzzing, or DoS (Denial of Service) attacks. They don’t provide shell access but are invaluable for gathering information and testing system stability.

2. </rich_text>
    <rich_text weight="heavy">Exploit Modules</rich_text>
    <rich_text>: These contain code to exploit specific vulnerabilities in target systems, such as buffer overflows or SQL injections. Exploit modules are used to gain unauthorized access to systems.

3. </rich_text>
    <rich_text weight="heavy">Payload Modules</rich_text>
    <rich_text>: Payloads are the code delivered to the target after a vulnerability has been exploited. They provide the means to execute commands, start reverse shells, or maintain persistent access.

4. </rich_text>
    <rich_text weight="heavy">Post-Exploitation Modules</rich_text>
    <rich_text>: These are used after initial access to gather further information, escalate privileges, or pivot to other network targets.

5. </rich_text>
    <rich_text weight="heavy">Encoders</rich_text>
    <rich_text>: Help obfuscate payloads to bypass detection mechanisms like antivirus software. They don't encrypt payloads but modify the code structure to evade basic signature detection.

6. </rich_text>
    <rich_text weight="heavy">NOP Generators</rich_text>
    <rich_text>: These are simple modules to create "no-operation" instructions, often used to align memory addresses for exploits.


</rich_text>
    <rich_text scale="h3">Payload Types</rich_text>
    <rich_text>
• </rich_text>
    <rich_text weight="heavy">Staged Payloads</rich_text>
    <rich_text>: Divided into two parts: a small stager that connects back to the attacker’s machine and downloads the larger stage payload. Staged payloads save space but rely on successful network communication.

• </rich_text>
    <rich_text weight="heavy">Non-Staged Payloads</rich_text>
    <rich_text>: Delivered in a single step. These do not rely on additional network communication, making them more reliable but larger in size.



</rich_text>
    <rich_text scale="h4">Stage and Stager</rich_text>
    <rich_text>
◇ </rich_text>
    <rich_text weight="heavy">Stager</rich_text>
    <rich_text>: The initial, smaller payload responsible for establishing a connection back to the attacker, preparing the way for the larger stage.

◇ </rich_text>
    <rich_text weight="heavy">Stage</rich_text>
    <rich_text>: The main payload that delivers functionality, such as Meterpreter, once the stager has successfully connected back.



</rich_text>
    <rich_text scale="h3">Meterpreter Payload</rich_text>
    <rich_text>
Meterpreter (short for </rich_text>
    <rich_text style="italic">Meta-Interpreter</rich_text>
    <rich_text>) is an advanced, flexible payload within Metasploit. Once deployed, Meterpreter operates solely in memory, making it difficult to detect. It provides several powerful features:
◇ </rich_text>
    <rich_text weight="heavy">In-memory Execution</rich_text>
    <rich_text>: Reduces detection by running solely in memory and avoiding disk writes.

◇ </rich_text>
    <rich_text weight="heavy">Command Modules</rich_text>
    <rich_text>: Allows execution of post-exploitation commands, such as gathering system information, capturing screenshots, recording keystrokes, and accessing the file system.

◇ </rich_text>
    <rich_text weight="heavy">Session Migration</rich_text>
    <rich_text>: Facilitates moving the Meterpreter session to a different process on the target machine, often for persistence or stealth purposes.

◇ </rich_text>
    <rich_text weight="heavy">Network Pivoting</rich_text>
    <rich_text>: Enables tunneling network traffic through the compromised host, useful for accessing internal network resources.


INSTALLATION
sudo apt-get update &amp;&amp; sudo apt-get install metasploit-framework -y
sudo systemctl enable postgresql 
sudo systemctl start postgresql
sudo systemctl status postgresql
sudo msfdb 
sudo msfdb init
sudo msfdb reinit 
sudo msfdb status
msfconsole 
# :D
</rich_text>
  </node>
</cherrytree>
